#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/arunkumar-palaniappan-65446814 (LinkedIn)

#### Top Skills

Encryption HTTPS Java

# Arunkumar Palaniappan

Full stack Java Developer

Englewood, Colorado, United States

## Summary

14+ years of experience as software professional with expertise in all facets of software and product development including high proficiency in Java, J2EE, SQL and JavaScript frameworks. Having good exposure to Agile methodologies and team management. Good at working in fast paced, demanding environment both independent and part of a team.

Skills:

Language: Java, J2EE

Middle Server Layer: Spring, Spring-Boot, Spring MVC, Hibernate,

Spring REST, Spring Data JPA, JDBC, JSP, Servlets

Frontend: Angular JS, JQuery, ExtJS, Bootstrap, OpenLayers

Datastore: Oracle DB, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, LDAP Build Tool: Apache Maven, Apache Ant, Gradle, Jenkins

Deployment Environment: Windows, Linux, Azure Kubernetes

Service

Version Control Tools: GitHub, GitLab, Tortoise SVN Code Quality: HCL Appscan, Veracode, GHAS CodeQL DB tools: SQL Developer Tool, MongoDB Compass

Agile Tools: Rally, Jira

Encryption: SSL/TLS on HTTPS, Self-Signed certificate creation,

Java Keytool, OpenSSL

Containerization: Docker, Kubernetes Agile Tools: Rally, Jira, Assembla

Worked on IBM Watson Health products

## Experience

Virtusa

10 years 4 months

Lead Consultant

August 2022 - Present (2 years 11 months)

#### Senior Consultant

March 2015 - September 2022 (7 years 7 months)

Denver, Colorado, United States

I started to work on Virtusa from March 2015 at Chennai, India and Moved to USA on September 2018. I worked on various projects at Virtusa on various technologies like Java, Spring, Spring Boot, AngularJS, JQuery, Oracle DB, Mongo DB etc.

Roles and Responsibilities at Virtusa:

- Develop and engineer high level designs for converting requirements into business processes using Java and Java Enterprise (J2EE)
- Perform detail design work for workflows, business rules, user interfaces and reports.
- Actively participate in the requirements, design and construction phases and guide project delivery from a

high-level technical perspective.

- Work with offshore development team on technical issues on-site as needed
- Participate in discussions with customers to crystallize business requirements and change requests.
- Conduct unit testing and integration testing with the development team and bug fixing with the testing team with input from product management
- Reviewing the peer codes for better code quality

kCube Consultancy Services Pvt Ltd Systems programmer February 2008 - March 2015 (7 years 2 months) Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

I started to work on kCube Consultancy services from February 2008 at Chennai, India as a Geomatics Technician One. I worked on various Web GIS projects in the technologies like Java, Servlets, jQuery, ExtJS, PostgreSQL, Tomcat etc.

Roles and Responsibilities at kCube:

- Worked on different client projects and it covers Requirement gathering, designing, developing, testing, and deploying and maintenance.
- Work with team members, guide junior members and assign the tasks to them.
- Versioning the projects by commit or update the changes using Tortoise SVN.

- Interact with client directly through Skype for requirement gathering and bug fixing.
- Provide suggestions to client on project improvements.
- Worked on create or clone the windows server on AWS EC2 console
- Learn new technologies and advanced versions to improve the current projects GUI and performance.

### Education

College of Engineering, Guindy
Bachelor of Engineering - BE, GeoInformatics · (June 2004 - April 2007)

Sri Ramakrishna Mission Vidyalaya Polytechnic College Diploma of Education, Diploma in Civil and Rural Engineering · (June 2001 - April 2004)